<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:43:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Web Development VS Code Settings, theme, Extensions, tips and tricks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/my-web-development-vs-code-settings-theme-extensions-tips-and-tricks</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/my-web-development-vs-code-settings-theme-extensions-tips-and-tricks</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:42:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[I have been using a lot of editors and IDE's since I began programming.
Eclipse, Netbeans, Notepade++, Brackets Editor, Sublime Text 2, Sublime Text 3, Webstorm, Atom Editor and probably some more I forgot.

Currently, I'm using Visual Studio Code. According to google trends, it is also the most searched editor. There are some excellent reasons for that.

vs code feels fast. It is tough to get vs code to slow down. Usually, it is not the fault of vs code but a poorly implemented extension.

File search is super fast. It feels instant. Like there is no wait time.

It is lightweight but also has most of the things you need pre-installed. Search files, debugging, basic git GUI.

Nice theme support and customization support. You can pretty much change everything in vs code.

Excellent extensions! Think of an extension you need? Yeah vs code has that!]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Performance Tune a JavaScript Website with Chrome DevTools]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/performance-tune-a-javascript-website-with-chrome-devtools</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/performance-tune-a-javascript-website-with-chrome-devtools</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 04:42:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Measuring the performance of JavaScript web applications is an important way to give your users the speed they expect. We'll discuss a few Chrome DevTools that can help us measure the performance of our applications.

JavaScript powers lots of websites and web applications on the web today. These websites and applications are expected to be blazing fast if we plan to retain our users. Accurately measuring the performance of web applications is an important aspect of making web applications faster.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Auto Refreshing Cache in .NET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/auto-refreshing-cache-in-net</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/auto-refreshing-cache-in-net</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 02:09:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[On a bright sunny day while you’re working on your awesome project you catch a glimpse of something. You bring yourself closer to the monitor and begin meticulously examining your code. What you find brings you feelings of disgust and shame! You’ve been calling an API retrieving data you need over and over again even though said data hardly changes!

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operating a Large, Distributed System in a Reliable Way: Practices I Learned]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/operating-a-large-distributed-system-in-a-reliable-way-practices-i-learned</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/operating-a-large-distributed-system-in-a-reliable-way-practices-i-learned</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 02:07:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[For the past few years, I've been building and operating a large distributed system: the payments system at Uber. I've learned a lot about distributed architecture concepts during this time and seen first-hand how high-load and high-availability systems are challenging not just to build, but to operate as well. Building the system itself is a fun job. Planning how the system will handle 10x/100x traffic increase, ensuring data is durable, regardless of hardware failures is intellectually rewarding. However, operating a large, distributed system has been an eye-opening experience for myself.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASP.NET Core gRPC Services]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/aspnet-core-grpc-services</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/aspnet-core-grpc-services</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 02:07:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Originally developed at Google, gRPC today is a remote procedure call (RPC) framework that has emerged as an alternative to RESTful and HTTP-based interfaces to connect remote components and specifically microservices. The new RPC framework was created in part to work with modern technologies such as HTTP/2 and Protobuf.

The gRPC framework offers native bindings for a number of programming languages, including C#, and using it from within ASP.NET and ASP.NET Core microservices has never been an issue. It’s worth mentioning, though, that earlier .NET implementations of gRPC wrapped native DLLs and kept the service hosted on its own server. In .NET Core 3.0, however, a gRPC service is a full .NET implementation hosted on Kestrel, like other ASP.NET Web applications. This article explores the Visual Studio 2019 project template and the dedicated ASP.NET Core layer.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Managing a Secure JSON Web Token Implementation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/managing-a-secure-json-web-token-implementation</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/managing-a-secure-json-web-token-implementation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 02:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This article assumes that you have a working knowledge of how JSON Web Tokens are both used and represented. If you would like to learn more about JSON Web Tokens, you can check out this article by Auth0: An Introduction to JSON Web Tokens.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>