<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 16:23:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <category>Videos</category>
        <category>Events-training</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using Auth0 with Static Web Apps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/using-auth0-with-static-web-apps</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/using-auth0-with-static-web-apps</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 16:04:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[One of my favorite features of (the now General Available) Azure Static Web Apps (SWA) is that in the Standard Tier you can now provide a custom OpenID Connect (OIDC) provider. This gives you a lot more control over who can and can’t access your app.

In this post, I want to look at how we can use Auth0 and an OIDC provider for Static Web Apps.

For this, you’ll need an Auth0 account, so if you don’t already have one go sign up and maybe have a read of their docs, just so you’re across everything.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is your ASP.NET server so slow? 10 performance problems and solutions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/why-is-your-aspnet-server-so-slow-10-performance-problems-and-solutions</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/why-is-your-aspnet-server-so-slow-10-performance-problems-and-solutions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:54:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Server performance problems can happen for many different reasons. Memory issues, slow database requests, and too few machines are just some of them. I witnessed my fair share of problems and learned a few tricks along the way. In this article, I’ll tell you about 10 types of issues that can cause performance problems in your server. That’s not to say I categorized all possible problem types, but these might give you some ideas and nudge you in the right direction next time you’re digging into perf matters.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Prem To The Cloud: Rub Some DevOps On It (episode 3)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/on-prem-to-the-cloud-rub-some-devops-on-it-episode-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/on-prem-to-the-cloud-rub-some-devops-on-it-episode-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Abel and Damian talk about why DevOps is important for on prem applications. They'll walk through creating a CI/CD pipeline for our VM-based application and database using Azure Pipelines and GitHub Actions.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Problem Details for Better REST HTTP API Errors]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/problem-details-for-better-rest-http-api-errors</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/problem-details-for-better-rest-http-api-errors</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:52:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[How do you tell your API Consumers explicitly if there are errors or problems with their request? Everyone creating HTTP APIs seems to implement error responses differently. Wouldn’t it be great if HTTP API Errors had a standard? Well, there is! It’s called Problem Details (https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7807)

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building Our First Microservice | The Xamarin Show]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/building-our-first-microservice-the-xamarin-show</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/building-our-first-microservice-the-xamarin-show</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:51:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This week, James is joined by Nish Anil who is here to walk us through building our very first Microservice for our mobile apps with .NET, ASP.NET Core, Docker, Kubernetes, and more! He shows how to switch from development to production without changing a line of code with the power of Microservices!]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing Windows Community Toolkit v7.0]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/announcing-windows-community-toolkit-v70</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/announcing-windows-community-toolkit-v70</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:50:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[After many months of invigorating the Windows Community Toolkit with a multitude of improvements and features; we are happy to announce version 7.0 is available today! Made possible again with the support and contributions of our developer community.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing .NET Multi-platform App UI Preview 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/announcing-net-multi-platform-app-ui-preview-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/announcing-net-multi-platform-app-ui-preview-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:49:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[With .NET 6 Preview 3 we are shipping the latest progress for mobile and desktop development with .NET Multi-platform App UI. This release adds the Windows platform with WinUI 3, improves the base application and startup builder, adds native lifecycle events, and continues to add more UI controls and layout capabilities. We are also introducing new semantic properties for accessibility. As we explore each of these in a bit more detail, we invite you to dotnet new along with us and share your feedback.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cloud-Native learning resources for .NET developers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/cloud-native-learning-resources-for-net-developers</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/cloud-native-learning-resources-for-net-developers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Today, users are demanding responsiveness, the latest and greatest features, and zero downtime from their applications. Businesses are rapidly adopting the cloud’s power to meet user demand, increase scalability and availability of applications. However, to fully embrace the cloud and optimize cost savings, applications need to be designed with the cloud in mind. This means not just changing the way applications are built, but also changing development practices in the organization to adopt this cloud-native architectural style.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>