<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 04:02:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-source HTTP API packages and tools]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/open-source-http-api-packages-and-tools</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/open-source-http-api-packages-and-tools</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 03:59:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[We’re continuing our series on building HTTP APIs with .NET 5. In the previous post, we covered Creating Discoverable HTTP APIs with ASP.NET Core 5 Web API. In this post, we’ll go further with a look at using open-source HTTP API packages and tools. Let’s dig in!

Creating Discoverable HTTP APIs with ASP.NET Core 5 Web API
Open-source HTTP API packages and tools
Visual Studio Connected Services
App Building with Azure API Management, Power Apps, and Logic Apps
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Staying safe with .NET containers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/staying-safe-with-net-containers</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/staying-safe-with-net-containers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 03:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Container-based application deployment and execution has become very common. Nearly all cloud and server app developers we talk to use containers in some way. We mostly hear about public cloud use, but also IoT and have even heard of .NET containers pulled and used over satellite links on cruise ships. In the early days, we would share compelling reasons why people should consider containers. We no longer do that because containers are so widely used now. We are focused on making .NET a great container platform, and adapting as the container ecosystem evolves.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azure App Service, Health checks and zero downtime deployments]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/azure-app-service-health-checks-and-zero-downtime-deployments</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/azure-app-service-health-checks-and-zero-downtime-deployments</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 03:54:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[I've been working recently on zero downtime deployments using Azure App Service. They're facilitated by a combination of Health checks and deployment slots. This post will talk about why this is important and how it works.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SQL Formatter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/sql-formatter</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/sql-formatter</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 03:52:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[SQL Formatter is a JavaScript library for pretty-printing SQL queries. It started as a port of a PHP Library, but has since considerably diverged.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Best Machine Learning Laptops]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/10-best-machine-learning-laptops</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/10-best-machine-learning-laptops</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 03:49:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Machine learning is a wide branch of Artificial Intelligence. It gives machines the power to learn and grow all by themselves based on the provided big data. The machine learning frameworks and IDE needs a powerful device to work as many memory-intensive tasks are to be executed on these devices.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>