<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:15:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A developer's guide to Ignite 2020]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/a-developers-guide-to-ignite-2020</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/a-developers-guide-to-ignite-2020</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:13:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite will take place online, kicking off on the morning of September 22nd, at 8:00 AM in the Pacific Time Zone. The event programming will include live segments, digital breakout sessions, and Q&A, available across multiple time zones. Be sure to visit the Ignite home page to view the event agenda and additional details.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GitHub CLI 1.0 is now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/github-cli-10-is-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/github-cli-10-is-now-available</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:13:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[GitHub CLI brings GitHub to your terminal. It reduces context switching, helps you focus, and enables you to more easily script and create your own workflows. Earlier this year, we announced the beta of GitHub CLI. Since we released the beta, users have created over 250,000 pull requests, performed over 350,000 merges, and created over 20,000 issues with GitHub CLI. We’ve received so much thoughtful feedback, and today GitHub CLI is out of beta and available to download on Windows, macOS, and Linux.

With GitHub CLI 1.0, you can:

Run your entire GitHub workflow from the terminal, from issues through releases
Call the GitHub API to script nearly any action, and set a custom alias for any command
Connect to GitHub Enterprise Server in addition to GitHub.com
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Approval Tests: Write Tests More Quickly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/approval-tests-write-tests-more-quickly</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/approval-tests-write-tests-more-quickly</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:11:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Sometimes assert code in tests gets big and messy and complicated when the output we’re testing is complex.

Approval Tests is a library that can help simplify assert code. The library has other benefits/use cases which I’ll cover in future posts such as using human intelligence to judge if the output is correct; providing a safety net when refactoring legacy code that has no tests; and even testing view rendering.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Entity Framework Core with PostgreSQL – base configuration]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/entity-framework-core-with-postgresql-base-configuration</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/entity-framework-core-with-postgresql-base-configuration</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 16:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[A different way of implementing the persistence layer in .Net Core & Entity Framework Core combination – Npgsql PostgreSQL. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating ASP.NET Core Microservices in AWS using SAM and CloudFormation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/creating-aspnet-core-microservices-in-aws-using-sam-and-cloudformation</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/creating-aspnet-core-microservices-in-aws-using-sam-and-cloudformation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 14:19:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this article, let's talk in-detail about building Microservices in ASP.NET Core with more focus on deploying these services as individual silos interfaced by an API gateway in AWS cloud, as a single stack using Serverless Application Model aka SAM.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wrapping JavaScript libraries in Blazor WebAssembly/WASM]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/wrapping-javascript-libraries-in-blazor-webassembly-wasm</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/wrapping-javascript-libraries-in-blazor-webassembly-wasm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 06:05:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this article, we will show how you can wrap a JavaScript library in Blazor and thereby getting that one feature into Blazor WebAssembly.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cross-platform diagnostic tools for .NET Core]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/cross-platform-diagnostic-tools-for-net-core</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/cross-platform-diagnostic-tools-for-net-core</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 08:11:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[A good reminder. It's been this way for a half decade but I'm still bumping into folks who have never heard this. Moving forward, .NET 5 will be a unification of the .NET Framework you may have heard for years, and the new .NET Core I like talking about, PLUS great goodness, tools and libraries from Mono and Xamarin. It's one cross-platform .NET with a number greater than 4. Because 5 > 4, natch.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>