<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 02:50:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[C# and gRPC Part One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/c-and-grpc-part-one</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/c-and-grpc-part-one</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 22:49:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[gRPC is a modern open source RPC framework created by Google. It is based on Google’s modern Protocol Buffer serialization engine but is not tied to it. C# developers who have used WCF in the past, or anyone building C# backend services should take a look at this. gRPC has most of the functionality that WCF has, but you can build on .NET Core. This article will introduce gRPC, explain why WCF developers should pay attention, and talk about why it could be used for any service. According to Scott Hunter at Microsoft:

If you are a remoting or WCF Server developer and want to build a new application on .NET Core, we would recommend either ASP.NET Core Web APIs or gRPC

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Candidate Features For C# 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/candidate-features-for-c-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/candidate-features-for-c-9</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 22:48:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The long road to C# 9 has already begun and this is the first article in the world about the C# 9 Candidate features. Once you have completed reading this article, you will hopefully be better prepared for the new C# challenges you will meet in the future.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[netcore-kubernetes-profiling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/netcore-kubernetes-profiling</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/netcore-kubernetes-profiling</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 22:48:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This is my personal collection of notes, scripts and techniques developed to help debug live .NET Core applications. All of these techniques were performed from a sidecar in Kubernetes. If you are interested in profiling .NET Core applications running on Linux without Kubernetes then these guides still will contain a lot of useful information.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>