<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 22:19:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Libraries-Tools</category>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <category>Videos</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[web-worker]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/web-worker</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/web-worker</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 22:15:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Native cross-platform Web Workers. Works in published npm modules.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating web apps via TypeScript and webpack]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/creating-web-apps-via-typescript-and-webpack</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/creating-web-apps-via-typescript-and-webpack</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 22:15:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This blog post describes how to create web apps via TypeScript and webpack. We will only be using the DOM API, not a particular frontend framework. The repository ts-demo-webpack with the files can be downloaded from GitHub.

Required knowledge: It helps if you have a rough understanding of how TypeScript, webpack, and npm work.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Things I Wished More Developers Knew About Databases]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/things-i-wished-more-developers-knew-about-databases</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/things-i-wished-more-developers-knew-about-databases</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 22:14:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[A large majority of computer systems have some state and are likely to depend on a storage system. My knowledge on databases accumulated over time, but along the way our design mistakes caused data loss and outages. In data-heavy systems, databases are at the core of system design goals and tradeoffs. Even though it is impossible to ignore how databases work, the problems that application developers foresee and experience will often be just the tip of the iceberg. In this series, I’m sharing a few insights I specifically found useful for developers who are not specialized in this domain.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CSS is hard, Blazor and Tailwind CSS makes it easier]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/css-is-hard-blazor-and-tailwind-css-makes-it-easier</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/css-is-hard-blazor-and-tailwind-css-makes-it-easier</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:22:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[I really enjoy full stack web development.

Nothing quite beats that feeling of taking a feature all the way from concept to working software, from airy fairy idea to something you can actually interact with in the browser.

But, for all the good days when I enjoy building software, there are the bad days…

You know these days.

These are the days when you seriously question your life choices, when it feels like you spent the entire day pushing pixels around only to fail, spectacularly, to get anything that vaguely resembles the design brief up and running on the screen.

For me, these are my CSS days.

I hate working with CSS.

OK, maybe “hate” is putting it a bit strong, but it’s crazy frustrating when I know I can build entire features, make them perform miracles technically, and work exactly as they’re supposed to, but the end result looks like something my five year old put together.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Simple Retry Policy with Polly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/simple-retry-policy-with-polly</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/simple-retry-policy-with-polly</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:21:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Exceptions in production are a matter of course for any distributed application like a web app. Instead of just crashing the application when an error occurs we can sometimes be a little smarter. In this episode we take a look a the Polly library for handling transient faults.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating and Packaging a .NET Standard library]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/creating-and-packaging-a-net-standard-library</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/creating-and-packaging-a-net-standard-library</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this post we will cover how you can create a .NET Standard library and then share that with other developers via NuGet. We will be demonstrating this with Visual Studio for Mac, but you can also follow along with Visual Studio, or Visual Studio Code when using the dotnet CLI. If you are on macOS, and haven’t already download Visual Studio for Mac you can download it here. We will create a new .NET Standard library from scratch, configure it for NuGet and then publish to nuget.org. The sample library will be a logging package.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Build a Simple Pokémon Web App with React Hooks and the Context API]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/how-to-build-a-simple-pokemon-web-app-with-react-hooks-and-the-context-api</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/how-to-build-a-simple-pokemon-web-app-with-react-hooks-and-the-context-api</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:19:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[After seven years of full stack development using Ruby, Python, and vanilla JavaScript, these days I mostly work with JavaScript, Typescript, React, and Redux.

The JavaScript community is great and moves really fast. Tons of things are created "overnight", usually figuratively, but sometimes literally. All this makes it is really difficult to keep up to date.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time Series Forecasting in ML.NET and Notebooks in Azure ML Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/time-series-forecasting-in-mlnet-and-notebooks-in-azure-ml-studio</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/time-series-forecasting-in-mlnet-and-notebooks-in-azure-ml-studio</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this sample, learn how to run time series forecasting in a Jupyter notebook. We will read in data from a csv file, do some exploratory plots, fit a regression model, and fit a more sophisticated Singular Spectrum Analysis (SSA) forecaster.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to run locally build docker images with Kubernetes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/how-to-run-locally-build-docker-images-with-kubernetes</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/how-to-run-locally-build-docker-images-with-kubernetes</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:16:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[To run Kubernetes in your local environment, Minikube is your choice. Minikube is a lightweight Kubernetes implementation that creates a Virtual Machine on your local machine and deploys a simple cluster containing only one node. By default, Minikube will always pull the docker images from the docker repository. To test locally build docker images with Minikube, you got to tell Minikube to refer them from your local system, instead of fetching from the docker registry. There are various ways to tell Minikube to look for local docker images. In this post, we’ll see how to run locally build docker images with Kubernetes.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intro to Azure CLI for Azure SQL]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/intro-to-azure-cli-for-azure-sql</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/intro-to-azure-cli-for-azure-sql</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 20:14:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this video, Anna Hoffman and Jeroen ter Heerdt discuss and show how you can get started with Azure CLI and the Azure Cloud Shell with respect to Azure SQL. For more info, see https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cli/azure/sql/db?view=azure-cli-latest&WT.mc_id=dataexposed-c9-niner.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cloud Concepts - Principles of cloud computing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/cloud-concepts-principles-of-cloud-computing</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/cloud-concepts-principles-of-cloud-computing</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 19:08:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Explore the core concepts of cloud computing and how it can help your business.

In this module, you will:

Explore common cloud computing services
Explore the benefits of cloud computing
Decide which cloud deployment model is best for you]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>