<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week 51 Year 2019</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/51/year/2019?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 19:07:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <category>Videos</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 reasons why you should learn C# in 2020]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/15-reasons-why-you-should-learn-c-in-2020</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/15-reasons-why-you-should-learn-c-in-2020</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 13:46:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Understand d the role of C# in the software development industry and why it is such a loved and productive language. C# is a well-designed language in high demand in top software companies around the world. Deciding to invest in mastering C# can be one of the best career decision you can make in 2020.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Implementing GitHub Actions for an Azure Static Website]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/implementing-github-actions-for-an-azure-static-website</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/implementing-github-actions-for-an-azure-static-website</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:14:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[While I was doing the work to host my Blazor search app within my website I realised I'd need to update the deployment pipeline I use for my blog. The process being used was very similar to the one used for the DDD Sydney website, but tweaked for use with Hugo. As it was setup a while ago I used the UI designer in Azure Pipelines, not the YAML approach so this seemed like the perfect opportunity for an overhaul.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Up Next: .NET 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/up-next-net-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/up-next-net-5</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:10:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Now that Microsoft has shipped .NET Core 3.1, the next stop on the .NET Core roadmap is just plain old .NET 5 with no "Core" and no "Framework" -- it's all just .NET from here on.

Due in November 2020, .NET 5 will mark the company's transformation from the aging, proprietary, Windows-only .NET Framework to a modern, open-source, cross-platform .NET.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Front-end Developer Handbook 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/front-end-developer-handbook-2019</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/front-end-developer-handbook-2019</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:09:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This is a guide that everyone can use to learn about the practice of front-end development. It broadly outlines and discusses the practice of front-end engineering: how to learn it and what tools are used when practicing it in 2019.

It is specifically written with the intention of being a professional resource for potential and currently practicing front-end developers to equip themselves with learning materials and development tools. Secondarily, it can be used by managers, CTOs, instructors, and head hunters to gain insights into the practice of front-end development.

The content of the handbook favors web technologies (HTML, CSS, DOM, and JavaScript) and those solutions that are directly built on top of these open technologies. The materials referenced and discussed in the book are either best in class or the current offering to a problem.

The book should not be considered a comprehensive outline of all resources available to a front-end developer. The value of the book is tied up in a terse, focused, and timely curation of just enough categorical information so as not to overwhelm anyone on any one particular subject matter.

The intention is to release an update to the content yearly. This is currently the fourth year an edition has been released.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing SandDance: Data Visualization in Azure Data Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/introducing-sanddance-data-visualization-in-azure-data-studio</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/introducing-sanddance-data-visualization-in-azure-data-studio</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:08:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[SandDance provides data visualization in the context of the data you are operating in and gives you interactive data exploration where you can quickly find pattern, trends and anomalies from the data. It's rich interactive 3D viewer gives the effects of different attributes on the data and its ease of use provides data engineers with a powerful in place tool to visualize their data. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Practices - Async / Await | The Xamarin Show]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/best-practices-async-await-the-xamarin-show</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/best-practices-async-await-the-xamarin-show</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This week, James is joined by friend of the show Dean Faizel, Microsoft Mobile Customer Advisory Team Engineer, who talks us through the best practices of using async and await in mobile development.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s new in XAML developer tools in Visual Studio 2019 for WPF & UWP]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/whats-new-in-xaml-developer-tools-in-visual-studio-2019-for-wpf-and-uwp</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/whats-new-in-xaml-developer-tools-in-visual-studio-2019-for-wpf-and-uwp</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:00:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Since the launch of Visual Studio 2019 we’ve released many new features for XAML developers working on WPF or UWP desktop applications. With this week’s release of Visual Studio 2019 version 16.4 and 16.5 Preview 1 we’d like to use this opportunity to do a recap of what’s new throughout the year. If you missed our previous releases or simply have not had a chance to catch-up, this blog post will be the one place where you can see every major improvement we’ve made throughout 2019.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Democratize AI with Azure Machine Learning designer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/democratize-ai-with-azure-machine-learning-designer</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/democratize-ai-with-azure-machine-learning-designer</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 08:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Azure Machine Learning has a large library of algorithms from the classification, recommender systems, clustering, anomaly detection, regression and text analytics families. Each is designed to address a different type of machine learning problem. In this demo, you will learn how to use Azure Machine Learning designer in a few simple steps and create an end-to-end machine learning pipeline for your data science scenario.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Create serverless applications (7 hr 30 min)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/create-serverless-applications-7-hr-30-min</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/create-serverless-applications-7-hr-30-min</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 07:59:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Azure Functions enable the creation of event-driven, compute-on-demand systems that can be triggered by various external events. Learn how to leverage functions to execute server-side logic and build serverless architectures.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pinnable Properties: Debug & Display Managed Objects YOUR Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/pinnable-properties-debug-and-display-managed-objects-your-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/pinnable-properties-debug-and-display-managed-objects-your-way</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 07:57:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[A few months ago, I wrote a blog post about the DebuggerDisplay attribute. This is a managed attribute that lets you customize how you view objects in debugging windows by “favoriting” specific properties. Since that post, we’ve streamlined DebuggerDisplay’s behavior with Pinnable Properties, a new managed feature available for Visual Studio 16.4!

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ultimate guide to secure cookies with web.config in .NET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/the-ultimate-guide-to-secure-cookies-with-webconfig-in-net</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/the-ultimate-guide-to-secure-cookies-with-webconfig-in-net</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 07:09:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[How to secure your cookies in ASP.NET and MVC, using Secure and HttpOnly attributes. Also, learn about Cross-site tracing and Cross-site request forgery.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demystifying the new .NET Core 3 Worker Service]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/demystifying-the-new-net-core-3-worker-service</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/demystifying-the-new-net-core-3-worker-service</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 18:38:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Premier Developer Consultant Randy Patterson discusses the benefits of using the new Worker Service project template introduced in .NET Core 3.

.NET Core 3 introduced a new project template called Worker Service. This template is designed to give you a starting point for cross-platform services. As an alternate use case, it sets up a very nice environment for general console applications that is perfect for containers and microservices.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getting Started with Python in Visual Studio Code]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/getting-started-with-python-in-visual-studio-code</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/getting-started-with-python-in-visual-studio-code</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 18:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Robert is joined by Tyreke White, who shows us how to get started with Python development using Visual Studio Code. He covers what you need to install and how to configure your environment, as well as sharing tips on how to debug your Python code.  

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Run C# natively in the browser through the web assembly via mono-wasm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/run-c-natively-in-the-browser-through-the-web-assembly-via-mono-wasm</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/run-c-natively-in-the-browser-through-the-web-assembly-via-mono-wasm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 14:47:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[We all heard about WASM, capabilities, and possibilities. Other languages and runtimes such as Rust have their official way to run their code in the browser and for .NET, the only official way is to use Blazor which is a front-end framework.

Blazor is good, but it’s a complete package for developing the whole frontend application. What if I like to use .NET libraries inside my old JS application that is already in production?]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>