<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week undefined Year undefined</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/undefined/year/undefined?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:32:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <category>Libraries-Tools</category>
        <category>Videos</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azure Static Web Apps are Awesome]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/azure-static-web-apps-are-awesome</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/azure-static-web-apps-are-awesome</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:16:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Over the last 3 months or so, I’ve been building a lot of experimental software on the web. Silly things, fun things. And throughout, I’ve wrangled with different ways to host modern web content.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenTelemetry .NET Beta Released!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/opentelemetry-net-beta-released</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/opentelemetry-net-beta-released</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:07:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Today, we are happy to announce that the OpenTelemetry .NET SDK has reached beta. This means that you can now begin integrating the OpenTelemetry .NET SDK into your applications and libraries to capture and export metrics and traces.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In-Memory caching in ASP.NET Core]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/in-memory-caching-in-aspnet-core</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/in-memory-caching-in-aspnet-core</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:52:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Here is how you can speed up your ASP.NET Core Application's Response time by over 50-80%.

The Topics covered are as follows.

1. What is Caching?
2. Caching in ASP.NET Core
3. What is In-Memory Caching in ASP.NET Core?
4. Pros and Cons of In-Memory Caching
5. Endpoint to Get / Set Cache in Memory
6. Practical Cache Implementation

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using .NET Core Tools to Create Reusable and Shareable Tools & Apps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/using-net-core-tools-to-create-reusable-and-shareable-tools-and-apps</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/using-net-core-tools-to-create-reusable-and-shareable-tools-and-apps</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:32:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Starting with .NET Core 2.1 Microsoft introduced the Dotnet Tools platform as part of the .NET Core SDK and since then these tools have become a vital although underutilized part of the .NET Eco system.

Dotnet Tools are a simple way to create, publish and consume what are essentially .NET Core applications that can be published and shared using the existing NuGet infrastructure for packaging and distribution. This means it's really quick and easy to build tools that you can share either publicly or privately.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learn about the latest .NET Productivity features]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/learn-about-the-latest-net-productivity-features</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/learn-about-the-latest-net-productivity-features</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:31:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The .NET Productivity team (a.k.a. Roslyn) is constantly thinking of new ways to make .NET developers more productive. We’ve been working hard to take the feedback you’ve sent us and turn it into tools that you want! In this post, I’ll cover some of the latest .NET productivity features available in Visual Studio 2019.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build High-performance Microservices with gRPC and .NET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/build-high-performance-microservices-with-grpc-and-net</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/build-high-performance-microservices-with-grpc-and-net</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[gRPC is a high-performance RPC framework designed for microservices. In this talk you will learn how to use gRPC in .NET and see how gRPC's support for deadlines and cancellation can be used to create fast, reliable microservice apps.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monitoring .NET Core applications on Kubernetes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/monitoring-net-core-applications-on-kubernetes</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/monitoring-net-core-applications-on-kubernetes</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:28:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Prometheus is an open source monitoring solution that collects metrics from the system and its applications. As a developer, you can query these metrics and use them to create alerts, which you can use as a source for dashboards. One example would be using Prometheus metrics with Grafana.

In this article, I show you how to use Prometheus to monitor a .NET Core application running on Kubernetes. Note that installation instructions are not included with the article. I do include a reference for using the Prometheus Operator to create and configure Prometheus on Kubernetes.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Love Azure Static Web Apps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/i-love-azure-static-web-apps</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/i-love-azure-static-web-apps</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:25:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[As a web developer, I have fully embraced the idea that to extract pure performance out of our web applications we need to reduce the amount of time that a server needs to churn on request. Statically generated web sites really scratch that itch.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learning How to Transition Your SQL Server Skills to Azure SQL]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/learning-how-to-transition-your-sql-server-skills-to-azure-sql</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/learning-how-to-transition-your-sql-server-skills-to-azure-sql</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:23:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Are you interested in learning how to translate your existing SQL Server expertise to Azure SQL including Azure SQL Database and Azure SQL Managed Instance? In this episode, Bob Ward, Anna Hoffman, and Marisa Brasile announce all-new content on YouTube, Github, and Microsoft Learn to help you become an Azure SQL professional. And, to support you as you learn, you can join Bob & Anna in four-day series of live sessions: aka.ms/azuresqlbootcamp

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getting Started: Apache Kafka with .NET Core]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/getting-started-apache-kafka-with-net-core</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/getting-started-apache-kafka-with-net-core</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 19:23:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[If you’re interested in playing around with Apache Kafka with .NET Core, this post contains everything you need to get started.

I’ve been interested in Kafka for awhile and finally sat down and got everything configured using Docker, then created a .NET console app that contained a Producer and a Consumer.

Here’s my complete process of what that involved.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blazor GameDev – part 7: animations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/blazor-gamedev-part-7-animations</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/blazor-gamedev-part-7-animations</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 02:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Hi my fellow gamedevs! Welcome back to part 7 of our Blazor 2d Gamedev series. Today we’re going to step into the marvelous world of animations using spritesheets 🙂]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azure Fundamentals — Almost all you need to know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/azure-fundamentals-almost-all-you-need-to-know</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/azure-fundamentals-almost-all-you-need-to-know</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:50:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Let’s start with the reason why any cloud is a cheaper option than others: Economies of Scale. Economy of scale is the ability to reduce costs and gain efficiency when operating at a larger scale in comparison to operating at a smaller scale. Cloud services offer high availability, fault tolerance, agility, scalability, elasticity, global reach, disaster recovery, security and lots more.

It involves moving away from CapEx (Capital expenditure — server / storage / network upfront costs) into OpEx ( Operational Expenditure — deductible expense on cloud services used). The following diagram shows how with CapEx you are always playing catch up and are either under-provisioned or over-provisioned most of the time, whereas with OpEx model you depend on a cloud service to autoscale (up or down) and then pay the appropriate costs for rendered services later (no upfront costs).]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shifting from Express.js to Azure Functions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/shifting-from-expressjs-to-azure-functions</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/shifting-from-expressjs-to-azure-functions</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 18:08:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Express.js is one of the most popular Node.js frameworks for web developers and remains an excellent choice for building apps that serve API endpoints.

When migrating code to a serverless architecture, refactoring Express.js endpoints affects the following areas:

Middleware: Express.js features a robust collection of middleware. Many middleware modules are no longer required in light of Azure Functions and Azure API Management capabilities. Ensure you can replicate or replace any logic handled by essential middleware before migrating endpoints.

Differing APIs: The API used to process both requests and responses differs among Azure Functions and Express.js. The following example details the required changes.

Default route: By default, Azure Functions endpoints are exposed under the api route. Routing rules are configurable via routePrefix in the host.json file.

Configuration and conventions: A Functions app uses the function.json file to define HTTP verbs, define security policies, and can configure the function's input and output. By default, the folder name that which contains the function files defines the endpoint name, but you can change the name via the route property in the function.json file.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Performance with Profiling Part 3: Profiling and Production]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/performance-with-profiling-part-3-profiling-and-production</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/performance-with-profiling-part-3-profiling-and-production</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 04:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In part 3 of our multi-part series on performance profiling, PM Esteban Herrera shows us how to profile apps once they are in production. 

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>