<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week 28 Year 2019</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/28/year/2019?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 11:40:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Azure Certification: Where to Start?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/microsoft-azure-certification-where-to-start</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/microsoft-azure-certification-where-to-start</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:28:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The question of “Where to start with Microsoft Azure Certification?” is a common one. Navigating the gauntlet of certification paths and exams can seem a bit daunting at first. This article is specially written to help ease the pain involved, so you can save time searching and find some useful information right here. Now, let’s discuss the topics of “Where do I start?” in regards to Microsoft Azure certifications.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Write Better Code Faster with Roslyn Analyzers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/write-better-code-faster-with-roslyn-analyzers</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/write-better-code-faster-with-roslyn-analyzers</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:27:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Roslyn, the .NET compiler platform, helps you catch bugs even before you run your code. One example is Roslyn’s spellcheck analyzer that is built into Visual Studio. Let’s say you are creating a static method and misspelled the word static as statc. You will be able to see this spelling error before you run your code because Roslyn can produce warnings in your code as you type even before you’ve finished the line. In other words, you don’t have to build your code to find out that you made a mistake.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Investigating identity threats in hybrid cloud environments]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/investigating-identity-threats-in-hybrid-cloud-environments</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/investigating-identity-threats-in-hybrid-cloud-environments</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:27:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[As the modern workplace transforms, the identity attack surface area is growing exponentially, across on-premises and cloud, spanning a multitude of endpoints and applications. Security Operations (SecOps) teams are challenged to monitor user activities, suspicious or otherwise, across all dimensions of the identity attack surface, using multiple security solutions that often are not connected. Because identity protection is paramount for the modern workplace, investigating identity threats requires a single experience to monitor all user activities and hunt for suspicious behaviors in order to triage users quickly.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Writing Java with Visual Studio Code]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/writing-java-with-visual-studio-code</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/writing-java-with-visual-studio-code</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:26:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This tutorial shows you how to write and run a simple Hello World program in Java with Visual Studio Code. It also covers a few advanced features, which you can explore by reading other documents in this section.

If you run into any issues when following this tutorial, you can contact us by clicking the Report an issue button below.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.NET Reunified: Microsoft’s Plans for .NET 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-reunified-microsofts-plans-for-net-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-reunified-microsofts-plans-for-net-5</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[When Microsoft announced .NET 5 at Microsoft Build 2019 in May, it marked an important step forward for developers working across desktop, Web, mobile, cloud and device platforms. In fact, .NET 5 is that rare platform update that unifies divergent frameworks, reduces code complexity and significantly advances cross-platform reach.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Repository Pattern C#]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/repository-pattern-c</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/repository-pattern-c</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:25:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[A Repository mediates between the domain and data mapping layers (like Entity Framework). It allows you to pull a record or number of records out of datasets, and then have those records to work on acting like an in-memory domain object collection, and you can also update or delete records within those data set, and the mapping code encapsulated by the Repository will carry out the appropriate operations behind the scenes.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Versioning limitations in .NET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/versioning-limitations-in-net</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/versioning-limitations-in-net</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 13:25:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This is a blog post I’ve intended to write for a very long time. (Other blog posts in that category include a recipe for tiramisu ice cream, and “knights and allies”.) It’s one of those things that’s grown in my mind over time, becoming harder and harder to start. However, there have been three recent incidents that have brought it back into focus:

Azure Functions and Grpc.Core versioning conflict
Grpc.Core considering a major version bump
Recent internal discussions that would involve a major version bump for all the Google Cloud libraries I maintain]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.NET Unit Testing: Spend Upfront to Save Later On]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-unit-testing-spend-upfront-to-save-later-on</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-unit-testing-spend-upfront-to-save-later-on</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 08:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Unit tests are a very powerful tool and are simpler than you may think. The article explores unit testing and what tools are available in DotNet such as Microsoft.VisualStudio.TestTools and Moq.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Repository Pattern C#]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/repository-pattern-c</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/repository-pattern-c</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 07:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Repository Pattern in C# supports the objective of achieving a clean separation and one-way dependency between the domain and data mapping layers. This article is a complete guide to Repository Pattern in C#.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing: ASP.NET Interview Questions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/introducing-aspnet-interview-questions</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/introducing-aspnet-interview-questions</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 06:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This is a curated sampling of ASP.NET interview questions.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>