<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dotNET Weekly - Week 4 Year 2021</title>
        <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/week/4/year/2021?feed=rss</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 07:00:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>Videos</category>
        <category>Articles</category>
        <category>Events-training</category>
        <category>Libraries-Tools</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Create MVC App With Google Authentication (and Identity)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/create-mvc-app-with-google-authentication-and-identity</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/create-mvc-app-with-google-authentication-and-identity</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:54:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This video shows you how to Authenticate an MVC app with Google in DotNet5. It shows you how to build this app from scratch using the command line and delves into the google interface briefly all the way through logging in after running the app.
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Create and deploy a cloud-native ASP.NET Core microservice]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/create-and-deploy-a-cloud-native-aspnet-core-microservice</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/create-and-deploy-a-cloud-native-aspnet-core-microservice</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:49:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In this module, you will:

Examine existing ASP.NET Core microservices running in Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS).
Implement a new ASP.NET Core microservice and containerize it.
Publish the Docker image to Azure Container Registry (ACR).
Deploy the Docker container to the existing AKS cluster.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.NET Conf]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-conf</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-conf</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:46:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[.NET Conf: Focus on Windows is a free, one-day livestream event that features speakers from the community and Microsoft teams working on Windows desktop apps and making them fantastic on the latest .NET 5. Learn why and how to upgrade WPF and Windows Forms apps to .NET 5, see Visual Studio tooling improvements, learn how to leverage cloud services from your client apps, and a whole lot more. You'll also see what the future of native device development with .NET will look like in .NET 6.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.NET 5 Networking Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-5-networking-improvements</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/net-5-networking-improvements</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:42:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[With .NET 5 released in November, it’s a good time to talk about some of the many improvements in the networking stack. This includes improvements around HTTP, Sockets, networking-related security, and other networking primitives. In this post, I will highlight some of the more impactful and interesting changes in the release.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 ways to save costs by running .NET apps on Azure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/5-ways-to-save-costs-by-running-net-apps-on-azure</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/5-ways-to-save-costs-by-running-net-apps-on-azure</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:42:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Digital transformation is accelerating at an incredible rate for consumers and employees alike, and the way we live and work has drastically changed. As a result, digital demand is surging, often past the capacity of existing infrastructure due to online demand for goods, services, and information. Businesses are shifting overnight from a physical first approach, to a digital first model putting strain on legacy web apps—both internal and external.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Design Patterns Explained with Food]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/design-patterns-explained-with-food</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/design-patterns-explained-with-food</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:40:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[GOF Design Patterns in C# with working examples inspired by food

This repository was made as a way to demonstrate and learn using moderately realistic examples of the Gang of Four Design Patterns (Design Patterns - Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software) by Gamma, Helm, Johnson, and Vlissides.

A YouTube series is in progress covering the details of each project. It starts here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C_6uQwBjsmk]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deep Dive into Open Telemetry for .NET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/deep-dive-into-open-telemetry-for-net</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/deep-dive-into-open-telemetry-for-net</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:39:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Open Telemetry is an open source specification, tools and SDK's used to instrument, generate, collect, and export telemetry data (metrics, logs, and traces). Open Telemetry is backed by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) which backs a mind boggling array of popular open source projects. It's worth looking at the CNCF Landscape to see what I really mean. The SDK's support all the major programming languages including C# and ASP.NET Core.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New release of Calzolari.Grpc.AspNetCore.Validation package !]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/new-release-of-calzolarigrpcaspnetcorevalidation-package</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/new-release-of-calzolarigrpcaspnetcorevalidation-package</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 04:00:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[New release of Calzolari.Grpc.AspNetCore.Validation package !
It supports now validation on streamed messages + some bugfixes.
Latest .NET 5 package: 5.1.0
Latest .NET Core 3.1 package: 3.3.0]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASP.NET Core Unit Testing with FluentAssertions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/aspnet-core-unit-testing-with-fluentassertions</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/aspnet-core-unit-testing-with-fluentassertions</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Writing and releasing a bug-free software product is a goal of every software developer and one of the tools to achieve this goal is unit testing. Unfortunately, the unit test coverage is not very high in many software projects and the main reason for this low coverage is that many developers think that they are either too busy in writing business logics and can’t give enough time to unit tests or they complain that most of the time unit tests written by other developers are not easy to read. Luckily, we have a library called FluentAssertions that makes our unit test look like the sentences written in plain English which are very easy to write and read by developers. In this tutorial, I will cover different features available in the FluentAssertions library so that you can also develop robust and bug-free software.

]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Figuring out Stages in YAML pipelines]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/figuring-out-stages-in-yaml-pipelines</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/figuring-out-stages-in-yaml-pipelines</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 22:55:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Stages are an essential part of a successful CI/CD pipeline. Discover how to use them and get the most value with Azure DevOps]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[🧩 Using C# Extension Methods for Auth0 Authentication]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/using-c-extension-methods-for-auth0-authentication</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/using-c-extension-methods-for-auth0-authentication</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:54:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[📚 How to use C# extension methods to simplify Auth0 configuration for ASP.NET web applications.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to fix Blazor WASM base path problems]]></title>
            <link>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/how-to-fix-blazor-wasm-base-path-problems</link>
            <guid>https://www.dotnetweekly.com/articles/how-to-fix-blazor-wasm-base-path-problems</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:17:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[This post will show you how to fix a common problem when setting the application base path with Blazor WebAssembly.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>